Autumn sees clear skies and stout horses, eh?
What does that mean?
It means horses fatten up in autumn because
that's when the best food is harvested.
These "horses" of yours
must be real gluttons.
Is her belly starting to stick out a bit?
Tempest sees clear skies
and stout Demon Lords...
It's autumn, all right.
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
Day 8: A Fruitful Autumn
It's said that only when basic needs
are met can one afford manners.
When the people's bellies are
full, their minds can relax,
and the nation can be its best,
with no unnecessary disputes.
That's how I want us to be.
Autumn is the season of bounty,
but it's also an important season
of preparation for winter.
Let's all work together to
harvest our crops today.
Right!
Okay, and next, our special guest—
I have awaited this day since the spring.
Sweet potatoes! Today, we will
dig up lots of sweet potatoes!
Yeah!
Uh, and some things besides
sweet potatoes, too...
Okay, next—
Everyone! Feed me lots of tasty foods!
Yeah!
Sweet potatoes!
Tasty!
These guests are completely unrestrained...
Sweet potatoes!
Tasty!
I'd like to confirm group A's
harvest schedule for today.
The goal is to complete four blocks by noon.
And group B
Harvest Schedule
Group A *Great Rimuru will come by to inspect.
Harvest of the test crops
Complete by noon
Group B
Harvest of the large field
Grains in blocks A and B
should complete the harvest of
blocks A and B by this evening.
We should have no trouble
finishing by tonight.
Uh-huh!
Ririna, the Goblin Lord,
is our production supervisor.
She's a quick thinker and a hard worker.
And above all, she's pretty.
Not one fault to be found.
Seriously?
That's hilarious!
Yo, yo, yo! Ya buncha slugs!
Hey, you lazy boys!
If you waste too much time,
we won't finish before it gets dark.
You keep slackin' off,
we're gonna lose daylight!
You wanna look like jackasses
in front o' Great Rimuru?
You don't want to disgrace yourselves
in Great Rimuru's presence.
Would you like to be folded in half, chopped up,
and turned into fertilizer? Give me your answer.
Want me to fold you in half,
chop you up, and feed you to these fields?
Huh? Huh?!
Don't ya wanna eat somethin' tasty
that ya busted yer butts for?
Do you not wish to partake in delicious
food that you worked hard for?
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Well, don'cha?
You do, don't you?
Y-Yes!
We're sorry!
The work is coming along well.
Uh, great.
I see you haven't changed
since the old days...
She's so competent.
I will show no mercy on this day,
even to you, Lady Milim.
Those are some big words, One Horn.
The name is Shion!
Yeah, that.
My skills have been called
the greatest among the
Ten Great Demon Lords...
Greatest Among the Ten Great Demon Lords
At Digging Up Sweet Potatoes
at digging up sweet potatoes.
Huh?
Well, the Legendary Ogre Goddess
known throughout the Forest of Jura
Legendary Ogre Goddess
is what they call me!
At Digging Up Sweet Potatoes
At digging up sweet potatoes!
Now!
It's on!
Digging Up Sweet Potatoes
As the greatest among the
Ten Great Demon Lords,
defeat is inconceivable!
Allow me to show you why
they call me a legend!
That's really how you two wanna do this?
I mean, it's working really well, but...
What a great haul.
I-I cannot allow a Dryad to demean
herself by digging up potatoes!
It's all right.
Dryads are born from potatoes, you see.
She's a cannibal?!
Look at that!
That all grew from the seedlings
we planted in spring!
Oh! What a grand sight it is!
Pretty amazing, isn't it?
Don't sing, though.
As you wish.
Magnificent!
It's like a golden carpet shining
in the light of the sun!
These plump ears of rice...
They symbolize the
fruitfulness of our nation!
What a great thing to say.
Don't dance, though.
As you wish.
Well, now that we're all
into it, let's get cutting!
I want to see that shiny new
rice as soon as possible!
How cruel, Great Rimuru!
The mere thought...
of this beautiful sight...
being taken away...
Sir Gabiru!
These guys are just a pain in
the neck from beginning to end.
Slime Diaries.
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
When sparring with Master Soei,
I can't lower my guard for even a moment.
I dodged it!
You like chestnuts?
Y-Yes...
Me, too.
The expedition team has
returned with provisions.
Oh, good work.
Wow! What a great harvest!
We owe it all to the Star Wolves' keen noses.
Let's see...
Whoa! Th-These are...
The color... The shape... The aroma!
It's the incredibly rare matsutake!
And so many of them!
Way to go!
Those things grow all over the place.
Huh?
They're not rare at all.
We just picked them on the way.
They probably won't taste that good.
Feel free to take as many as you like.
Oh! Ogre mushrooms!
We can get excellent stock from this!
These red fruits are so sweet!
Let me have some of the sour persimmons.
These look tasty, too!
You are quite unusual.
This is a really big one!
They're so cold sometimes.
With this many, we can
all enjoy them together!
This round shape makes me
so excited! Please throw it!
To be honest, I don't like
these that much, either.
We'll have a feast today.
Yes! Just leave it to me!
Hey, One Horn!
It's Shion.
Yeah, that!
What do you think of this?!
That's the best you can do?
What?!
Wh-Where did you find such
a huge sweet potato?!
Was it over there? Or over here?
Damn you! You're nothing but a One Horn!
It's Shion!
They're all duds...
What's the matter, Lady Milim?
No one knows how a battle ends...
until it's over!
Th-That sweet potato is...
The shape is so elegant.
I'm not sure what was going on,
but it just ended in a flash.
Heh... Found me, huh?
Slime Diaries.
Slime Diaries
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Great Rimuru, let's roast them right away!
I can't wait any longer!
All right! Let's make our
first roasted sweet potatoes!
Yay!
Roasted... sweet potatoes? What's that?
Just watch.
There!
Great Rimuru, I think it's ready now!
Okay.
Milim, bring the sweet potato
you want to roast, too.
Here's mine.
It's the biggest, most elegant one!
Wow...
There.
What do you think you're doing?!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Roasted sweet potatoes...
are a kind of food made by roasting
sweet potatoes slowly over a fire,
and it makes them shockingly delicious.
Notice
Notice.
The digestive enzyme beta-amylase breaks down
Digestive Enzyme
Beta-Amylase
starch that's become
gelatinous by high heat,
High Heat
Component
Starch
Gelatinous
Maltose
which creates maltose, making it taste sweet.
Gives food a sweet flavor
Creates
Huh?
In other words, all we
need to do now is wait.
All right.
I'll wait until it's done, then.
Roasted sweet potatoes!
It's so warm.
Slime Diaries!
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
That should do it.
Oh, dried persimmons!
Yeah. I got some from the expedition team.
You do love your sweets, Brother.
Do you want to join the League of Sweets?
I got my sweet tooth from Father.
Want this?
Father loved dried persimmons.
Even on the battlefield,
he kept some in his...
Oh, sorry for bringing back that memory.
What's that face for?
It's what you look like after
eating a sour persimmon.
Don't bring that memory back.
Well, that was the only one that came to me!
Cut it out. You're never
going to get married.
These look great.
Where should I put these?
I had no idea so many of them would grow.
Potatoes
Everyone worked hard to
keep the weeds at bay.
Managing farmland and creating an
environment where many plants can grow...
Lady Treyni!
It seems you two can hear the
voices of the plants now.
If Great Rimuru hadn't told us that
we could raise crops ourselves,
I never would have even imagined it.
Before I knew it, I could read the condition
of a seedling by examining its leaves.
Listen to the tiny voices of the plants...
You... Yes!
You want to be a fried potato!
You want to be a fried potato, do you?
Hey, what's that box?
Oh... Look, I think the sweet
potatoes are done roasting.
Yum!
What makes this so delicious?!
Well, we really did nothing but roast it...
What?! It's just roasted?!
Do you want another?
Yes!
How can something that felt
so hard and smelled like dirt
turn out so soft and sweet?
What kind of food did you
eat before coming here?
She must have grown up without any love.
I can relate.
She must've gotten angry because
she hates raw vegetables.
Prepare for divine punishment.
Are you crazy?! This is the finest
feast anyone could ask for!
Uh-huh...
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
Milim, your sweet potato's cooked!
I've been waiting for this!
Slime Diaries!
Sweet Potatoes
Hey!
The sweet potatoes are cooked!
All right!
Break time!
Wow!
I haven't had a roasted sweet potato in ages!
Who knew we could raise sweet
potatoes ourselves, huh?
It's so good!
So good!
Want some, Master?
Master's been acting kinda weird lately.
His eyes seem to go distant at random times,
and he just stands and stares
at the falling leaves...
I have no idea what his past
as a swordsman was like.
But every time I see his
back when he's like this...
I can't stop myself!
Punishment
Sweet Potatoes
Hey, we just thought you were going senile...
Y-Yeah.
I am very much all here, thank you.
Would you care to try again?
I don't have the time
to spare them a thought.
Everyone!
Great Rimuru has sent snacks for all of you.
How gracious of him to think of us...
Go on, eat up!
It's so soft and sweet!
We've already given the children
theirs, so help yourselves.
How great it is to have bountiful land.
Yes, we must take good care of it.
Sir Geld, what's the matter?
Don't worry about me. Go ahead and eat.
Sir Geld.
Let's all eat together.
Yes.
Eat well and grow strong.
Share your joy and grow strong.
We sure got a lot.
Impressive!
Looks like this year's harvest
is going to end pretty well.
Guess we have you to thank, Treyni-san.
I only offered some advice.
To first think for yourselves
and learn how to plan...
That was the promise.
I guess so.
Well, now that the harvest is complete,
there is no further work for me to do here.
Huh?
I believe...
you all can take care
of the rest on your own.
Great Rimuru, until we meet again.
No way... That was so sudden...
Oh, Great Rimuru?
Is something wrong?
Hey, just a second ago, there was...
Nah, it's nothing.
You're right. We'll meet again someday.
Thanks, Treyni-san.
There's no way she'll be here, huh?
Welcome!
Ah, welcome.
You are here!
Jeez, again with this!
What? I returned to prepare the potatoes.
We just fried them up!
Would you like one, Great Rimuru?
This place is great.
There's so much good food!
That's right. It is amazing.
It's the result of the effort
put in by each of the citizens.
Be more modest, Shion.
That's right, One Horn!
It's Shion.
Yeah, that!
Now, we should get out before we get dizzy.
By the way...
I'm testing out a new dessert made
with chestnuts and sweet potatoes.
What?! I wanna eat it!
Dessert so late at night? How sinful!
Oh?
Try not to
eat too much
I mean... I thought girls worried
about that sort of thing!
I was trying to help! Okay? Okay? Okay?!
Please don't be mad!
Enjoy the flavors of autumn in moderation.
Preview
I actually never gain any weight!
Yep!
Nor do I. All nutrients
go straight to my chest!
I guess the League of Sweets
is permanently disbanded.
N-Next time, "The Arrival of Winter."